Hello English Nerds, welcome back to EnglishPod.
哈喽英语书呆子们，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we're going to be looking at English slang and informal words used in the 1980s.
今天我们要学习20世纪80年代使用的英语俚语和非正式词汇。
So this is the next part of our decades dialogues.
这是我们“年代对话”系列的下一部分。
Exactly.
没错。
So the 1980s maybe for many of our listeners is a little bit more familiar and there are
对于很多听众来说，80年代可能更熟悉一些，而且有很多
a lot of phrases and a lot of words that were born in this decade and we still use them
短语和词汇诞生于这个年代，我们今天仍然在使用
today.
它们。
So we're going to learn those words and phrases in this dialogue.
所以我们要在这段对话中学习这些词汇和短语。
But before we start, we need to preview a couple of words.
但在开始之前，我们需要先预览几个单词。
Let's go now to vocabulary preview.
现在进入词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
So one of the words that we're going to hear in our dialogue is ride.
我们将在对话中听到的一个词是“ride”。
Is that your ride?
那是你的车吗？
So a ride.
所以“ride”这个词。
Normally, we know this word as a verb, right?
通常，我们知道这个词是动词，对吧？
To ride a bicycle.
骑自行车。
In this context, it's an informal way of referring to your car.
在这个语境中，它是非正式地指代你的汽车。
So a ride is a car.
所以“ride”就是汽车。
Yeah, so I just bought a new ride.
是啊，我刚买了一辆新车。
All right, well, maybe you'll take me for a ride in your new ride.
好吧，也许你会带我去兜风，坐你的新车。
In your new ride.
你的新车。
Yeah.
是啊。
All right.
好的。
And we're also going to be looking at this word loaded.
我们还要看这个词“loaded”。
He's loaded.
他很有钱。
So if you are loaded.
所以如果你“loaded”。
You're really rich.
你非常有钱。
You have a lot of money.
你有很多钱。
You are loaded with money.
你钱多得不得了。
So loaded and ride.
所以“loaded”和“ride”。
Those are two words for vocabulary preview.
这是词汇预览中的两个词。
And well, let's listen to our 1980s dialogue and see what happens.
好了，让我们听听80年代的对话，看看发生了什么。
Jim, what's up, man?
吉姆，怎么了，老兄？
Charlie, is that your ride?
查理，那是你的车吗？
It's butt ugly, dude.
丑爆了，老兄。
Don't be an airhead.
别犯傻了。
This is a 1969 Chevy Impala.
这是一辆1969年的雪佛兰Impala。
I just need to fix it up a bit.
我只需要稍微修整一下。
In a couple of months, this baby is going to be wicked.
几个月后，这宝贝会超酷的。
Not even.
才不是呢。
Check it out.
看看这个。
Now that's a fresh ride.
那才是一辆酷车。
Well, too bad the driver's a major dweeb.
可惜司机是个大呆瓜。
Anyone can have a car like that if their daddy's loaded like his.
谁都能有那样的车，只要他老爸像他老爸一样有钱。
He's coming this way.
他朝这边走过来了。
Be cool.
冷静点。
Hey, guys.
嘿，伙计们。
What do you think of my automobile?
你们觉得我的汽车怎么样？
Isn't it bad to the bone?
是不是酷毙了？
Word.
说得好。
The ladies are going to be lining up to get with you when they see you driving around
姑娘们看到你开着那辆车兜风，会排着队想跟你
in that car.
在一起的。
You really think so?
你真这么觉得？
For sure.
当然。
Awesome.
太棒了。
Psyche.
骗你的。
You totally fell for it.
你完全上当了。
You're a real scumbag, Charlie.
你真是个混蛋，查理。
When I do the nasty with the prom queen, we'll see who has the last laugh.
等我跟舞会皇后亲热的时候，看谁笑到最后。
Dude, don't have a cow.
老兄，别发火。
All right.
好的。
So typical high school students of the decade, right?
典型的那个年代的高中生，对吧？
Definitely very, very 80s.
绝对是，非常80年代。
Very 80s.
非常80年代。
And well, of course, you always have the situation with the cool kids and maybe the kids that
当然，你总会遇到酷孩子和可能不那么酷的孩子的情况，
are not so cool and well, they're making fun of him, right?
他们在取笑他，对吧？
Yeah, but they use some really cool words.
是啊，但他们用了一些很酷的词。
So let's look at them now in Language Takeaway.
现在让我们在“语言要点”中看看它们。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
So the first word that we saw in Language Takeaway and was really interesting, this
我们在“语言要点”中看到的第一个词非常有趣，
word butt ugly.
这个词是“butt ugly”。
It's butt ugly.
丑爆了。
That car is butt ugly.
那辆车丑爆了。
So when something is butt ugly, it's really ugly, right?
所以当某物“butt ugly”时，就是非常丑，对吧？
It's very ugly.
非常丑。
It's not just ugly.
不只是丑。
It's very ugly.
是非常丑。
And what would butt is like from your bottom.
“butt”就像你的屁股。
From your bottom, yeah.
从你的屁股来的，是啊。
So he said the car was butt ugly and the other guy answered by saying, hey, don't be an airhead.
所以他说那辆车丑爆了，另一个人回答说，嘿，别当个傻瓜。
An airhead.
傻瓜。
Don't be an airhead.
别当个傻瓜。
So an airhead is someone with air in their head.
所以“airhead”是指脑袋里空的人。
In their head.
脑袋里。
So they're not very smart.
所以他们不太聪明。
They've got no brain.
他们没脑子。
They've got no brain, right?
他们没脑子，对吧？
So he said, don't be an airhead.
所以他说，别当个傻瓜。
Don't be such an idiot.
别这么白痴。
All right.
好的。
Now for the third word, he described his car as being wicked.
现在第三个词，他形容他的车是“wicked”。
It's wicked.
超酷的。
Wicked.
That's wicked.
那太酷了。
It's gonna be wicked.
它会超酷的。
Okay.
好的。
So this is a very 80s way of saying it's gonna be cool.
这是一种非常80年代的说法，表示它会很酷。
Yeah.
是啊。
It's gonna be awesome.
它会很棒的。
It's gonna be wicked.
它会超酷的。
All right.
好的。
And now when they saw another car pulling up, a new car, he described it as a fresh
现在当他们看到另一辆车开过来，一辆新车时，他形容它是“fresh ride”。
ride.
一辆酷车。
It's a fresh ride.
Now we understand that ride is a car, right?
现在我们明白“ride”是汽车，对吧？
So a fresh ride.
所以“fresh ride”。
It's another way of saying cool.
这是另一种表示酷的说法。
Okay.
好的。
So kind of similar, wicked and fresh.
所以有点类似，“wicked”和“fresh”。
Now finally, at the end of our dialogue, they said, you're a real scumbag, Charlie.
最后，在对话的结尾，他们说，你真是个混蛋，查理。
So this word scumbag is interesting.
所以这个词“scumbag”很有趣。
You're a scumbag.
你是个混蛋。
A scumbag.
一个混蛋。
Yeah.
是啊。
It's interesting and it's still used today, I would say.
它很有趣，而且我觉得今天还在用。
Yeah.
是啊。
So when someone is a scumbag, they're just really not a nice person.
所以当一个人是“scumbag”时，他们真的不是好人。
Yeah.
是啊。
They're not nice or they're not maybe to a certain point, honest.
他们不友好，或者可能在一定程度上不诚实。
They're not kind.
他们不善良。
Exactly.
没错。
So you're a scumbag.
所以你是个混蛋。
Okay.
好的。
But it's not a very harsh word, right?
但这并不是一个很严厉的词，对吧？
It's not harsh to call somebody a scumbag?
叫别人混蛋不严厉？
Well, it's not like a swear word, but it's certainly not a nice thing to say to someone.
嗯，它不像脏话，但肯定不是对别人说的好话。
Okay.
好的。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So let's listen to all these adjectives that we've just looked at right now again in our
让我们在对话中再听一遍我们刚刚看过的所有这些形容词，
dialogue and then we'll come back and look at some more phrases.
然后我们回来再看一些短语。
Jim.
吉姆。
What's up, man?
怎么了，老兄？
Charlie, is that your ride?
查理，那是你的车吗？
It's butt ugly, dude.
丑爆了，老兄。
Don't be an airhead.
别犯傻了。
This is a 1969 Chevy Impala.
这是一辆1969年的雪佛兰Impala。
I just need to fix it up a bit.
我只需要稍微修整一下。
In a couple of months, this baby's going to be wicked.
几个月后，这宝贝会超酷的。
Not even.
才不是呢。
Check it out.
看看这个。
Now that's a fresh ride.
那才是一辆酷车。
Too bad the driver is a major dweeb.
可惜司机是个大呆瓜。
Anyone can have a car like that if their daddy's loaded like his.
谁都能有那样的车，只要他老爸像他老爸一样有钱。
He's coming his way.
他朝这边走过来了。
Be cool.
冷静点。
Hey, guys.
嘿，伙计们。
What do you think of my automobile?
你们觉得我的汽车怎么样？
Isn't it bad to the bone?
是不是酷毙了？
Word.
说得好。
The ladies are going to be lining up to get with you when they see you driving around
姑娘们看到你开着那辆车兜风，会排着队想跟你
in that car.
在一起的。
You really think so?
你真这么觉得？
For sure.
当然。
Awesome.
太棒了。
Psyche.
骗你的。
You totally fell for it.
你完全上当了。
You are a real scumbag, Charlie.
你真是个混蛋，查理。
When I do the nasty with the prom queen, we'll see who has the last laugh.
等我跟舞会皇后亲热的时候，看谁笑到最后。
Dude, don't have a cow.
老兄，别发火。
Okay.
好的。
Well, you know what, Marco?
嗯，你知道吗，Marco？
I love the 80s.
我喜欢80年代。
I love the language of the 80s.
我喜欢80年代的语言。
I love the music of the 80s.
我喜欢80年代的音乐。
And I'm really loving these phrases from the 80s.
我真的很喜欢这些80年代的短语。
So why don't we look at them now in Fluency Builder?
那我们为什么不在“流利度构建”中看看它们呢？
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
All right.
好的。
So on Fluency Builder today, let's take a look at these phrases that you were talking
在今天的“流利度构建”中，让我们看看你刚才提到的这些短语。
about.
第一个非常有趣。
And the first one is very interesting.
所以这两个家伙，他们在取笑另一个坐在好车里的人，
So these two guys, they were making fun of this other person that was in this nice car
他叫他大呆瓜。
and he called him a major dweeb.
大呆瓜。
A major dweeb.
他是个大呆瓜。
He's a major dweeb.
真是个大笑话。
What a major dweeb.
Now let's break this into two parts first.
我们先把它分成两部分。
Well, let's see what dweeb means.
嗯，我们先看看“dweeb”是什么意思。
Well, a dweeb is a very uncool person.
“dweeb”是一个非常不酷的人。
Okay.
好的。
So kind of similar to a nerd.
有点像书呆子。
Yeah.
是啊。
A small kind of guy with no power.
一个弱小、没本事的人。
Okay.
好的。
He's a dweeb.
他是个呆瓜。
Now, this word major.
现在，这个词“major”。
It just means big, really serious.
它只是表示大的，非常严重的。
So it's a way of emphasizing, right?
所以这是一种强调的方式，对吧？
Yeah.
是啊。
And you can say anything.
你可以说任何东西。
You can have a major anything like, oh, I've got a major headache.
你可以有“major”任何东西，比如，哦，我头疼得厉害。
Or I can say, I have a major problem this week.
或者我可以说，这周我有个大问题。
Okay.
好的。
So major, a very big problem.
所以“major”，一个非常大的问题。
Yep.
是的。
Now they're talking about this really cool car and the guy who was a bit of a dweeb,
现在他们在谈论一辆非常酷的车，还有那个有点呆的家伙，
he said, isn't it bad to the bone?
他说，这车是不是坏到骨子里了？
Bad to the bone.
坏到骨子里。
It's bad to the bone.
它坏到骨子里了。
All right.
好吧。
Now, this is also part of a famous song, bad to the bone, but what does it mean?
现在，这也是一首著名歌曲《Bad to the Bone》的一部分，但它是什么意思呢？
Well, when something is bad to the bone, it's super cool.
嗯，当某样东西“坏到骨子里”时，它超级酷。
It's like, it's so dangerous that it's cool.
就像，它危险到很酷。
Exactly.
没错。
It's very, very cool.
它非常非常酷。
It's bad to the bone.
它坏到骨子里了。
Now, this is not used anymore.
现在，这个说法已经不再用了。
No, no, no.
不，不，不。
Don't walk out of your house and use this phrase tomorrow.
别明天走出家门就用这个短语。
All right.
好吧。
So, but it's interesting to know because there is a famous song that has this phrase in it.
所以，但知道它挺有意思的，因为有一首著名的歌里有这个短语。
So bad to the bone.
所以，坏到骨子里。
All right.
好吧。
So the car was so cool.
所以那辆车太酷了。
It was bad to the bone that all of the ladies would be wanting to get with the driver.
它坏到骨子里，所有女士都想和司机在一起。
All right.
好吧。
So somebody wants to get with you.
所以有人想和你在一起。
He just wants to get with you.
他只是想和你在一起。
So if you want to get with someone, you want to have sex with them.
所以如果你想和某人在一起，你想和他们发生关系。
Right.
对。
So if you want to get with someone, basically, it means that you want to have sex with them.
所以如果你想和某人在一起，基本上，意思是你想和他们发生关系。
But there's another phrase that was used in the dialogue that means pretty much the same
但对话中用了另一个短语，意思差不多
thing.
一样。
Yeah.
是的。
To do the nasty.
做那事。
They're doing the nasty.
他们在做那事。
Okay.
好的。
Now, this was a very popular way of saying it in the 80s.
现在，这是80年代很流行的一种说法。
It means to have sex as well.
它也指发生关系。
Yeah.
是的。
To do the nasty is a little bit rude, isn't it?
“做那事”有点粗鲁，不是吗？
Yeah.
是的。
I think it's a little bit more direct.
我觉得它更直接一点。
Yeah.
是的。
If you and your friends are talking and you say, hey, I think that girl wants to get with
如果你和朋友聊天时说，嘿，我觉得那个女孩想和你
you, it's a little bit more casual and less obvious.
在一起，那就更随意，不那么明显。
Yeah.
是的。
Yes.
对。
Do the nasty is a little bit more rude.
“做那事”更粗鲁一点。
Yeah.
是的。
A little bit more direct.
更直接一点。
Yeah.
是的。
And now the last phrase that we're going to look at today was made famous by the cartoons,
现在，我们今天要看的最后一个短语因卡通片而闻名，
The Simpsons.
《辛普森一家》。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
And it's don't have a cow.
就是“别发火”。
Don't have a cow, man.
别发火，老兄。
Don't have a cow.
别发火。
So, to not have a cow.
所以，就是别发火。
Don't have a cow means?
“别发火”是什么意思？
To get really angry, to freak out, to get upset.
就是非常生气，抓狂，心烦意乱。
All right.
好吧。
So, now we know that you say don't have a cow, but can I say it and use it in the positive?
所以，现在我们知道你说“别发火”，但我能说它并用在肯定句中吗？
Can I say, hey, my boss totally had a cow today in the office?
我能说，嘿，我老板今天在办公室完全发火了吗？
Yeah.
是的。
And it means, again, so it freaked out, got angry, made a big deal of something.
它的意思又是，所以他抓狂了，生气了，小题大做了。
Okay.
好的。
He had a cow.
他发火了。
Yeah.
是的。
So, Frank's going to have a cow when he finds out I smashed his car.
所以，弗兰克发现我撞坏他的车时会发火的。
Of course Frank is going to have a cow.
弗兰克当然会发火。
How can you smash his car?
你怎么能撞坏他的车呢？
All right.
好吧。
But now it's time for us to listen to this dialogue for the last time and then we'll
但现在是我们最后一次听这段对话的时候了，然后我们会
come back and talk a little bit more about this decade of the 1980s.
回来再聊聊这个80年代。
Jim, what's up, man?
吉姆，怎么了，老兄？
Charlie, is that your ride?
查理，那是你的车吗？
It's butt ugly, dude.
它丑爆了，老兄。
Don't be an airhead.
别犯傻了。
This is a 1969 Chevy Impala.
这是一辆1969年的雪佛兰黑斑羚。
I just need to fix it up a bit.
我只需要稍微修一下。
In a couple of months, this baby is going to be wicked.
几个月后，这宝贝就会变得超棒。
Not even.
才不是呢。
Check it out.
看看这个。
Now, that's a fresh ride.
现在，那才是一辆酷车。
Well, too bad the driver's a major dweeb.
嗯，可惜司机是个大呆瓜。
Anyone can have a car like that if their daddy's loaded like his.
只要他老爸像他一样有钱，谁都能有那样的车。
He's coming this way.
他朝这边来了。
Be cool.
冷静点。
Hey, guys.
嘿，伙计们。
What do you think of my automobile?
你们觉得我的车怎么样？
Isn't it bad to the bone?
它是不是坏到骨子里了？
Word.
说得好。
The ladies are going to be lining up to get with you when they see you driving around
女士们看到你开着那辆车兜风时，会排着队想和你
in that car.
在一起的。
You really think so?
你真这么觉得？
For sure.
当然。
Awesome.
太棒了。
Psyche.
骗你的。
You totally fell for it.
你完全上当了。
You're a real scumbag, Charlie.
你真是个混蛋，查理。
When I do the nasty with the prom queen, we'll see who has the last laugh.
等我和舞会皇后做那事时，我们看谁笑到最后。
Dude, don't have a cow.
老兄，别发火。
Okay.
好的。
So, Marco, when I was listening to the dialogue this time, I heard a really cool word.
所以，马可，这次我听对话时，听到了一个很酷的词。
They said, psyche.
他们说了“骗你的”。
Right.
对。
And this was a very popular thing during the 80s when you would say to somebody, psyche.
这在80年代非常流行，当你对某人说“骗你的”时。
So this is like saying just kidding, right?
所以这就像说“开玩笑的”，对吧？
Just kidding, right.
开玩笑的，对。
So you would say, oh, Eric, I really like your hat.
所以你会说，哦，埃里克，我真的很喜欢你的帽子。
Oh, thank you.
哦，谢谢。
Psyche, that hat is terrible.
骗你的，那帽子太丑了。
Oh.
哦。
Right?
对吧？
So that's how you would use it.
所以这就是它的用法。
You would give somebody a compliment or you would lie to somebody and then tell them,
你会先夸某人或对某人撒谎，然后告诉他们
psyche, and then like tell them the truth like, oh, that hat is terrible or I was just
“骗你的”，接着告诉他们真相，比如“哦，那帽子太丑了”或“我只是
kidding.
开玩笑的”。
Okay.
好的。
So, psyche.
所以，“骗你的”。
That was a phrase.
那是一个短语。
It was very, very popular and when I was in school, we would use it as well.
它非常非常流行，我上学的时候，我们也会用。
We would psych each other out.
我们会互相捉弄。
So do we still use this phrase today?
那我们现在还用这个短语吗？
I don't think we use it today.
我觉得我们现在不用了。
I don't think it's cool anymore.
我觉得它不再酷了。
Well, if you'd use it, it's kind of like you're joking, right?
嗯，如果你用它，有点像在开玩笑，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
And I think it would make people laugh.
我觉得它会让人发笑。
Like, you know, it's pretty funny.
就像，你知道，挺有趣的。
Yeah.
是的。
You're joking about how you're a little bit old-fashioned.
你在开玩笑说你有点老派。
Exactly.
没错。
Yeah.
是的。
I'm very sure you would surprise a lot of your native English-speaking friends if you
我很确定，如果你用这个短语，你会让很多母语为英语的朋友
use this phrase.
感到惊讶。
A good one to try out.
一个值得试试的好词。
Now, if you have any questions about this phrase or any other of the language, come
现在，如果你对这个短语或任何其他语言有疑问，请
to our website at EnglishPod.com.
访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Right.
对。
We're there to answer all your questions and also let us know any other lessons or topics
我们会在那里回答你所有的问题，也请告诉我们你未来想学习的其他课程或
that you would like to learn about in the future.
话题。
Well, thanks for listening to this lesson, you guys.
好了，感谢收听这节课，各位。
And until next time, goodbye.
下次再见，拜拜。
Bye.
拜。